GERALD J PETRON

1785 Harrison St. Unit 209 Titusville, FL 32780 Phone: 321-663-2047 res16519gp@gmail.com

Occupation: Web Site Developer (see work sample demo: https://gp-web-dev.com)

Ability Summary:

Web site developer with 14 years experience designing, creating, and maintaining web sites.

Possesses practical experience in the development, deployment, administration, and application of web-page technologies, databases, and documentation systems, using AngularJS, Typescript, NodeJS, object oriented PHP, SQL, JavaScript, HTML5, and more.

Develops new front end applications and back-end domain server systems. Writes and maintains documentation to describe site/application development, coding, testing, changes, and corrections. Uses state of the art version control methodology for developing and tracking software. Writes efficient, testable, and maintainable code that is well documented. Comfortable with rapid and frequent customer-driven spec and feature changes.

Analyzes existing code to find causes of errors, vulnerability, and revises code as necessary. Troubleshoots problems, isolate issues, and implements solutions.

Upgrades legacy code to match modern industry expectations.

Provides technical assistance by responding to inquiries regarding errors, problems, or questions about websites and web-applications.

Experienced with Section 508 ADA compliance.

Web Development Skills:

AngularJS NodeJS React / NextJS

Typescript XML HTML5 / CSS

Object Oriented PHP Ajax Git Code Repository

MySQL/PostgresQL Javascript jQuery

Bachelor of Science Associate of Science

US Navy Veteran (Honorable Discharge) Valid Florida Driver's License

Employment History

Web Developer (retired since 09/2021)

06/2013 - 09/2021 M2 Systems https://m2-corp.com Altamonte Springs, FL

Website Development

- AngularJS frontend NodeJS backend SQL db (see online at https://onmimic.com)
- Medical imaging files and reports management
- Graphic data displays (bar graphs, pie charts, etc.)
- Patient / Doctor UI appointment scheduling, file tracking, storage, and viewing

Resume: Gerald J Petron, page 1 of 2

Web Developer (M2 Systems continued . . .)

Legacy Website Maintenance

- Object Oriented PHP
- Medical insurance records
- Extensive feature additions and enhancements
- ADA 508 Compliance upgrades

Supervisors: Leslie Purdy, Mark Davis, Michael Muscato

I grant permission to contact them for reference: 407-551-1330

Configuration Management Analyst

10/2006 - 04/2012

L-3 Communications, ALST

Orlando, FL

Web site development projects. Interactive database driven web sites using object oriented PHP programming language, Apache web-server, and MySQL database.

Design of web applications for data collection, analysis, and distribution to support local business processes. Examples: Action Tracking Database, Test Failure Reports, Rework Reports, Engineering Document Library, Quality System Documentation.

Database management and configuration management of Engineering, MRP, Quality System, and RMA documentation. MS Access software application development for Engineering Change Orders, Quality System, Training, Incoming Material Inspection, and RMA processing. MRP database management of inventory and BOM master tables. Report design and web page design for company wide data access. Change Control Board chairman.

Configuration Management Analyst

09/2003 – 09/2006 OSI Defense Systems, LLC Orlando, FL 03/2002 – 09/2003 Schwartz Electro Optics, Inc. Orlando, FL

Document control and configuration management policy.

Administration of engineering documentation database (AgileCM): control of user access rights and privileges; input and report form design.

Configuration management support to manufacturing, engineering, purchasing, quality, maintenance, and planning departments.

Data entry and Bill of Material maintenance of complex, configurable, electro-mechanical products.

Management of Engineering Change Order process. Authorship of process documents for all phases of document control and configuration management.

Education

- Advanced React Meta Course Certificate, Grade: 91%, 09-May-2024
- Florida Institute of Technology, Bachelor of Science, 1984
- ITT Technical Institute, Associate of Science, 1974

Resume: Gerald J Petron, page 2 of 2